woodenboat.com 2012-12-29

# Privacy Statement | WoodenBoat Magazine

WoodenBoat Publications, Inc., including its divisions, subsidiaries and affiliates (collectively hereinafter “WoodenBoat”), operates this web site (the “site”) in connection with its business. Visitors and users of the site are also referred to the Terms and Conditions for the site. WoodenBoat is committed to providing a safe and secure environment for its customers. Although WoodenBoat is not a “financial institution” that is governed by the Privacy of Consumer Financial Information Rule of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act, WoodenBoat is committed to respecting the privacy rights of guests and users of the site.

## Use of personal information

When you visit our forum, store, subscribe to our publications or training services on line, place a classified ad, or register with “Directory of Boat Plans and Kits,” we may ask you to provide information that personally identifies you (your “personal information”), for example, your name, address, email address, phone number, fax number, credit card number and expiration date, and/or other identifying information. We may also ask you for your birth date, your AIM ID, your occupation, your interests, and may allow you to post photographs of you and/or your boat. WoodenBoat uses your personal information to help identify you in the event you lose your password and to maximize you access to our online services and products. WoodenBoat does not sell or rent your personal information to third parties.

If you choose not to give us your personal information, you can still use most of our site, however, you will not be able to post on the forum, My WoodenBoat of the Week, our classified ads, sign up for classes, or order merchandise. WoodenBoat also tracks the domains from which the Site is visited and uses that data to analyze for trends and statistics, and then discards it. We do not track individuals — only instances of entry onto our site.

## WoodenBoat Forum

The WoodenBoat Forum allows you to post on our bulletin board (our “forum”) to communicate with other wooden boat enthusiasts. Although anyone can read your posts, posting to the forum is a restricted, password-entry-only service that is protected with a dedicated server, electronic and physical firewalls. When you register for our forum, you will be given the opportunity to “opt out” of email notices from our administrators and moderators; you will also be able to opt out of: having your email address viewable to others when you post on the forum; allowing other members to send you private messages; and notification by email when someone sends you a private message.

WoodenBoat may have its web site administrator, its forum moderator, and/or its editor(s) review our forum. In the event that you post information that violates the terms of use for our site (see Terms of Use), our administrator or moderator may remove your post and/or may change, lock, or delete your profile.

WoodenBoat currently maintains all posts to the forum online and the posts (except private posts and/or messages) are available for public viewing on its site. WoodenBoat retains the right to archive posts in the future at its discretion. In addition, posts may be lost or purged due to technical difficulties.

## “Cookies”

There is a technology called “cookies” which can be used to provide you with tailored information from a web site. A cookie is an element of data that frequently contains an anonymous unique identifier; the data is sent from the web site to your browser, which may then store it on your system for future use. Cookies are usually account identifiers and user preferences that allow you to speed through the log-in process by providing the data so that you do not have type it out.

Some WoodenBoat pages may use cookies so that we may better serve you when you return to our site. You can set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie, giving you the option to accept or reject it.

We use third‐party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [**click here**](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

## Security

If you buy anything from our store or sign up for one of our services, we ensure the security of your personal information by:

  1. keeping our databases and our web servers separate and protecting each with electronic and physical firewalls; and
  2. using Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption technology to transmit credit card information between your browser and our web servers.

WoodenBoat does not provide the technologies used to build its site, and therefore neither recommends nor endorses the same. Any information regarding identified technologies, their capabilities, limitations, applications, etc., should be sought directly from their manufacturers. WoodenBoat hereby disclaims any rights to trademarks, service marks, tradenames, logos, copyrights, patents, domain names or other intellectual property interests of third parties.

## Links to Other Materials

If any link is offered connecting to a third-party web site, it is as an accommodation to the respective third-party site owner and without charge. WoodenBoat reserves the right to reject any request for a link to a third-party web site and to remove any link for any reason. Sites linked to and from this site are not necessarily under the control of WoodenBoat and WoodenBoat shall have no responsibility or liability whatsoever for the content or privacy practices of any such linked site or any link or linking program at any time.

## Children’s Privacy

Persons under the age of thirteen (13) are not authorized to make purchases from the site or post on the forum, and WoodenBoat does not specifically collect information about children. However, WoodenBoat is concerned about the safety of children and their use of the Internet. Therefore, in accordance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998, WoodenBoat will never knowingly request or solicit personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13 without prior verifiable parental consent. In the event that WoodenBoat receives actual knowledge that WoodenBoat has collected such personal information without the requisite and verifiable parental consent, WoodenBoat will delete that information from its database as quickly as is practical.

## Effective Date and Changes

This Privacy Policy is effective as of April 15, 2003. WoodenBoat reserves the right to modify the terms of this Policy at any time and in its sole discretion, by posting a change notice on this page. Your continued use of the site following our posting of a change notice will constitute binding acceptance of those changes.

If you have any questions or suggestions, please contact us at:

Website Administrator  
WoodenBoat Publications, Inc  
P.O. Box 78  
41 WoodenBoat Lane  
Brooklin, Maine 04616, USA
